# Amila Madhushani Hikkaduwa Guruge

: +94 76 052 2377 | +94 70 486 9482 Phone : gurugeamilamadhushani@gmail.com **Email** 

**Nationality** : Sri Lankan | NIC : 977103185V

Gender : Female : 1997 - 07 - 28 Date of Birth Marital Status : Single

Address : No. 187 / B / 7, "Guruge Niwasa", Lenawara Uyana II, Haltota,

Bandaragama, Western Province, Sri Lanka.

### **PROFILE**

With more than three years of IT expertise in software development and IT teaching, I bring a versatile skill set encompassing data entry, database management, and various IT functions. Actively seeking opportunities in Dubai, I am poised to contribute adaptable technical skills to enhance data management processes and excel in diverse IT roles. Known for diligence and a commitment to excellence, I am eager to contribute to the success of IT-related functions in a new professional environment.

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# **Software Developer**

June 2023 - Present **SunTec Information Systems Pvt Ltd.** (https://suntecsolutions.com)

No:649, Galle Road, Rawathawatta, Moratuwa, Sri Lanka

- Gathered and analyzed customer requirements collaboratively.
- Designed and developed PHP-based systems.
- Managed databases using MS SQL Server and MySQL.
- Created stored procedures and functions.
- Configured and hosted web systems on virtual servers.
- Customized Inventry Management system, Information Management System and Learning Management System using PHP.
- Developed MIS reports using PHP mPDF, and PHP Excel

#### **ICT Demonstrator**

Sep 2019 - Sep 2021

Vocational Training Centre - Dehiwala (https://www.vtcdehiwala.lk)

Pallidora Rd, Dehiwala, Sri Lanka

- Handled practical aspect of the syllabus of Information & Communication Technology Technician Full Time Course (NVQ L4).
- Conducted comprehensive lessons on Microsoft Office packages Word, Excel, PowerPoint & Access.
- Provided hands-on guidance in Visual Basic, Photoshop and Illustrator, fostering creative and technical proficiency among students.
- Developed and delivered instructional content covering fundamental IT theories, ensuring a well-rounded understanding of basic IT concepts.

# **Trainee IT Technician**

July 2019 - Sep 2019

Ministry of Buddhasasana & Wayamba Development,

Colombo, Sri Lanka

- Successfully integrated data entry protocols into governemt system of the Ministry, enhansing the accuracy and accessibility of digital
- Simplifying the process of managing anf typing digital documents such as procurement documentation.

#### **EDUCATION**

B.Tech in Multimedia and Web Technology (Undergraduate) University of Vocational Technology, Ratmalana, Sri Lanka.	2024 - Reading
National Diploma in Information Technology - NDIT (NVQ L05)  National Vocational Training Institute, Narahenpita, Sri Lanka.	Jan 2022 - Dec 2023
Computer Hardware with Network Certificate Course Vocational Training Centre, Dehiwala, Sri Lanka.	Jan 2020 - July 2020
ICT NVQ Level 04 Qualified (TVEC)  Vocational Training Centre, Dehiwala, Sri Lanka.	Jan 2019 - July 2019
Diploma in English Vocational Training Centre, Dehiwala, Sri Lanka.	Jan 2018 - Dec 2018

English for Higher Education & Employment Course University of Colombo, Sri Lanka.	July 2016 - Dec 2016
G. C. E. Advanced Level in Bio Stream  Royal College, Horana, Sri Lanka.	2016
G. C. E. Ordinary Level Royal College, Horana, Sri Lanka.	2013

#### **SKILL HIGHLIGHT**

- System / Web Development (POS System | LMS | IMS | Payroll System)
- Database Handling
- Data Entry
- Graphic Designing
- Creativity
- Friendly
- Oral and written communication skills
- Problem Solving
- Manage Workplace Information
- Leadership
- Planning & Scheduling

#### **COMPUTER LITERACY**

■ Software Development : Java / C# / Visual Basic

■ Web Development : html / css / JavaScript / php / Boostrap

■ Database : My SQL / Oracle DB / MS SQL

■ Graphic Designing : Adobe Photoshop / Adobe Illustrator

■ MS Office Package : MS Word / MS Excel / Ms PowerPoint / MS Access

- Install & Troubleshooting of Operating Systems
- Software Installation and Troubleshooting
- Internet & E-Mail Operations
- Networking(LAN)

# **LANGUAGE**

Sinhala English

#### **ACCOUNTS**

Linkedin : https://www.linkedin.com/in/hgamilaamadhushani/

Behance: https://www.behance.net/amilaa\_guruge

# **DECLERATION**

I do hereby declare that the details given above are true and correct to the best of my knowledge and belief.